activeteachonline.com 2017-06-06

# Digital Learning Services Privacy Policy | Pearson UK

This Privacy Policy explains to our users and institutional customers how personal information will be used by Pearson in relation to our Digital Learning Services, which we refer to as the 'Services'.

By using these Services you are agreeing to the user terms and conditions which apply to the Services concerned, and to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to these conditions, please do not use these Services.

At Pearson we provide a number of Digital Learning Services, which aim to make learning more engaging for both adults and children.

Services linking to this Privacy Policy or referring to this Privacy Policy, are operated by Pearson Education Limited which is registered with the Information Commissioners Office under registration number Z8325164.  

Institutional customers who use these Services must get the necessary consent (in accordance with relevant privacy legislation) to upload personal information about teachers and learners to the Services. Institutional customers must also ensure that any personal information they upload is accurate.

If you have any doubt whether you have consent to upload the personal information, please do not use these Services.

As an institutional customer you are also required to maintain appropriate technical and organisational measures against unauthorised or unlawful processing of that personal information and against accidental loss, theft, destruction of or damage to that personal information. Passwords and user names for these Services should not be written down or shared. If you are a learning provider registering learners, please only upload school-issued email addresses for learners (not personal email addresses such as hotmail accounts). Legally as an institutional customer you are the data controller in respect of your teachers' and learners' personal information which is collected and used by the Services.

In an automatic operation the web server will collect users’ IP address and browser type and details of the website the user came from before entering these Services. This information is used to:

  * work out how many times these Services are visited;
  * record which parts of these Services have been visited so we can improve the content and layout of the Services.

This information is anonymous – it is not used to identify individual users. We may from time to time supply third parties with this anonymous data for uses in connection with our Services.

Find out more about how we use cookies at Pearson

Marketing will not be sent to any learners aged under 18 registered to use these Services unless consent has been provided on behalf of the learners.

Contact details for teachers and adult subscribers using these Services may be used for these purposes:

  1. to contact the user with more information about our products and services and those of our group companies, except where the user has told us not to
  2. to inform the user of activities on our Services
  3. to invite the user to participate in surveys, discussions and prize draws and ask for the user’s views on our Services via online surveys and discussion forums.

Participation in surveys and discussion forums is entirely voluntary. Users may unsubscribe from being contacted for these purposes at any time. Survey information will be used for market research with the aim of improving our Services.

We will not send marketing emails to a user who has opted out of receiving them. Any marketing communications we send will include an unsubscribe link at the end of the email.

Personal information which relates to these Services will be kept for a reasonable amount of time, and for a minimum of one calendar year after a subscription expires.

Any improper collection or misuse of personal information is a violation of this Privacy Policy and of our ‘Terms and Conditions’. Please report it by emailing [UKDataProtection@pearson.com](mailto:UKDataProtection@pearson.com).

All institutional customers and users must agree not to misuse any personal information available on these Services or to gather personal information or use robots or other automated scripts, codes or functionalities to do so.

We may immediately suspend or terminate users’ and institutional customers’ access without notice if we become aware that they are in breach of our Terms and Conditions or of this Privacy Policy.

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy or would like to make a subject access request (for which a £10.00 fee is charged), please do not hesitate to contact us at:

Data Protection Officer  
Pearson  
80 Strand  
London  
WC2R 0DT  
United Kingdom

or email us at [UKDataProtection@pearson.com](mailto:UKDataProtection@pearson.com).

This Privacy Policy is provided by Pearson Education Limited (registered number 872828, registered office 80 Strand, London, WC2R 0RL, United Kingdom) on its own behalf.

References in this Privacy Policy to "Pearson", "we", "us", "our" or similar refer to Pearson Education Limited.

In this Privacy Policy individuals who use the Services are referred to as “users”. Users could include learners and teachers, or individual subscribers who purchase access to the Services for themselves or for a child in their care.

When we refer to “institutional customers” we mean learning providers, such as schools and colleges, who purchase access to the Services for use in their institutions.

Limited personal information is collected during the registration process for these Services. As a guide we normally request the following data fields for learners: First Name, Last Name and Year Group, DOB, plus a school-issued email address where required (or a personal email address if an individual adult purchases access for their or their child’s personal use, rather than access being purchased by an institution). We do not usually collect personal addresses for learners where a service is sold through an institution. Limited personal information is also uploaded by learning providers for teachers: First Name, Last Name and Email address. If you would like to find out exactly what personal data will be collected as part of your service please contact [ukdataprotection@pearson.com](mailto:ukdataprotection@pearson.com).

Email addresses for learners are collected in order to be able to issue passwords securely through our systems. Please also refer to section 7 of this Privacy Policy to see how else email addresses may be used.

Institutional customers are responsible for ensuring that accurate information is uploaded to the Services. Please see institutional customer responsibilities outlined under section 3 of this Privacy Policy.

Learners and teachers may also generate personal information when using these Services. For example, the Services may record the number of points obtained by a learner, details of the books or activities a learner has read, and any learner/ teacher comments that have been entered as part of online exercises.  

The personal information that is collected about users will only be used to provide these Services and in accordance with this Privacy Policy. We will never sell users’ personal information and we will not pass users’ personal information to any third parties without the users’ consent except that we may disclose and share personal information:

with our service providers (for example, suppliers who develop or host our Services) – in which case we will require them to provide the same level of protection as provided by Pearson; and/or

  * if required or permitted by law; and/or
  * with relevant third parties (such as law enforcement agencies) if we reasonably believe a user may be in breach of the law (e.g. if a user has posted defamatory content on our Services);
  * with users’ school, employer or parent where the school, employer or parent has purchased access to the Services on the users’ behalf; and/or
  * with our group companies who may use the information in accordance with the Marketing Communications and the Opting Out section below. Please note information on learners aged under 18 will not be shared with group companies for marketing purposes.

We also use personal information in aggregate form (so that no individual user is identified by name) to build marketing profiles, audit how our Services are used, and to help with the strategic development of our Services.

At Pearson we will maintain appropriate technical and organisational measures against unauthorised or unlawful processing of personal information and against accidental loss, theft, destruction of or damage to personal information.

We seek to protect the safety of all personal information. In particular, provided a user’s browser accepts Secure Sockets Layer encryption, we seek to protect payment information against unauthorised access through a secure server. Where we use third parties to process personal information, we require them to ensure the safety of personal information. We use appropriate security measures on our own systems, but the internet is not a secure medium and we cannot guarantee the security of information transmitted via the internet. 

The personal information for these Services is usually hosted within the European Economic Area (EEA). If we contract service providers who will process personal data outside the EEA, we will require them to provide the same level of protection as provided by Pearson. Please see our commitment regarding what we will do with the personal information outlined in [section 6 of this Privacy Policy.

These Services may be aimed at learners aged under 18.

If a learner is under 18 and has any questions in relation to their personal information and these Services, we recommend that the questions are directed to their parent or legal guardian, or the learner’s teacher where relevant.

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will always include the date of a new version so that you know when there has been a change. If you don't agree to the changes, please don’t continue to use these Services or to provide us with your personal information.
